

ERIC PAUL

SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT & DEVELOPER

Portland, Or (971) 806.3088

multipurposegeek.ggmail.com multipurposegeek.com drupal.org/u/mpgeek

SKILLS

Team & Agile Collaboration

Collaboration, strong communication, technical strategy and planning, estimation, agile development practice, scrum

Concepts

Scalability + Performance, Object Oriented
Design/Programming (OOP), Test Driven
Development (TDD), Continuous
Integration/Delivery, Developer
Experience (DX) + DevOps, User
Experience (UX)

Languages & APIs

Linux/Mac BASH, Apache/NGINX, MySQL/MariaDB, PHP/Drush/Drupal/Wordpress, Behat/Mink, Web Services (REST/JSON), Git, Grunt/Node.js, Javascript/JQuery, S/CSS

Certifications

Acquia Certified Developer

SUMMARY

Software architect and developer with 12+ years of experience designing, implementing, and maintaining enterprise-class software with open source tools; data architecture, implementation, test, and deployment/delivery planning. Particularly interested in scalability and performance in software, along with process automation for standardizing development, deployment, and testing across teams that also implement software engineering best practices. Well-developed troubleshooting and diagnostic workflow skills. Comfortable mentoring and leading small development teams.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Developer

February 2016 - October 2017

Freeflow Digital

Application architecture and back-end development for registration-based applications built in Drupal 7 with multi-platform integrations including Salesforce for a global nonprofit, Banner Health. Full-custom solutions for tracking and syncing participant data across multiple systems to help facilitate early-detection research for brain-aging disorders. Live sites: https://endalznow.org, https://ftdregistry.org.

- Task management for a small team of developers. workflow management and process automation across environments.
- Documentation, knowledge sharing, and training across the technical team.
- Acquia-targeted architectures and semi-continuous delivery to Acquia environments.
- Linux system administration.

Key frameworks: Drupal/Drush, Entity API, Redhen CRM, Salesforce, Views, UUID, Features, Docksal, Jenkins, Behat, Simpletest, Bootstrap, Node.js/Grunt (GDT).

Developer

March 2013 - November 2015

Phase 2 / OpenSourcey (merger)

Full-stack Drupal development of enterprise-class translatable publishing platforms for online magazine applications (Time, Inc.), and a large-scale GIS/mapping solution for non-profit community site (VISTA).

- Implementation and delivery of scalable, performant solutions in a high-volume production environment.
- Architect and implement systems for developer workflow optimization in client environments, including continuous integration; virtual machine technology for developer environment standardization.
- Front-end architecture and integration for process automation.

Key frameworks: Drupal/Drush, Migrate, Workbench/Workflow, i18n/Entity Translate, Leaflet/Geocluster, OpenAtrium, Behat/Gherkin, Salesforce, Views, Profile2, UUID, Features, Bootstrap, Grunt/Node.js, Compass, Libsass.

Developer, Themer, Site Builder, User Support

2005 - 2013

Various Organizations

Developer - OakTree Digital

 Full-stack application design and implementation with Drupal 7. Requirements gathering/clarification, provisioning, site building, development, theming. Client-facing technical support.

Developer, Themer, Trainer - Portland State University

Web application development, testing, and maintenance, mostly in Drupal. Enterprise site
building, theming, development and upgrade management for the University's main Drupal
instance hosting a 200+ multisite.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering

2002 - 2008

Portland State University (Portland, OR)

Microelectronics, computer architecture, hardware/software integration, electronic design automation.